(East Palace)
Your Highness,
you're finally awake.
I was so afraid that you...
I've returned safely, haven't I?
Besides, my body
is slowly getting better.
But I clearly heard from our men
that you almost...
I just feel sorry for you,
Your Highness.
Why didn't you tell
the Commandery Princess
that you went
to find the cordyceps yourself?
If she doesn't have feelings for me,
even if she knew,
she would just find another way
to repay the favor.
Go tell her I'm back.
I'll go see her tomorrow.
But your health...
I miss her.
(Vibrant and Dazzling)
Your Highness,
what's wrong with you?
(Vibrant and Dazzling)
Your Highness.
What's wrong with you?
I won't see her today.
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 9=
From the look on your face,
is my condition
extremely bad?
Your Highness, the past ten years
of excruciating pain you've endured
have all been for nothing.
You've returned to the time
when you were most deeply poisoned,
living on borrowed time.
This relapse is severe.
The poison can no longer be controlled.
I can only temporarily
release some of the poison
to alleviate it.
But your eyes
can no longer distinguish colors.
This is already
the best possible outcome.
If we can't find an antidote,
your six senses will gradually fade.
After that,
your internal organs will fail.
How much time do I have left?
Five years at most.
If you have another acute relapse,
you'll only have three years left.
Tian Yuan.
I was thinking,
since I only have
three to five years to live,
I shouldn't get involved
with Commandery Princess anymore.
Your Highness,
we have three to five years.
The world is vast.
We can definitely find an antidote.
But I can't let her gamble with me.
What if there's no hope?
She's still in the prime of her life.
She'd have to live a lonely life.
How cruel would that be to her?
Your Highness,
Commandery Princess Zhaoning
requests an audience.
I won't see her.
Your Highness!
From now on,
if Commandery Princess comes,
I won't see her under any circumstances.
Yes.
Did the Crown Prince really say that?
Your Highness,
His Highness did say
he was already resting
and wouldn't see anyone.
Please, help me give this box
of cold-warding incense to His Highness.
His Highness also instructed
that he won't accept any gifts either.
Your Highness, please go back.
I always thought the Crown Prince
was so good to you.
Who knew that when he turns cold,
he could be so arrogant?
Your Highness,
let's go back to the Duke's Manor.
(Contemplating the Pine Breeze)
This is the medical record
of a close friend of mine.
I'd like to ask you to take a look
for me, Physician Xie.
Is he in good health?
This person's body is weak.
He has been ill for a long time.
And based on the medical record,
his old illness has relapsed.
His eyes
can no longer distinguish colors.
can't see colors?
This is just a superficial symptom.
His lifespan...
He only has three to five years left.
Are you sure?
If he is your dear friend,
then you should
show him more care and concern.
Your Highness.
It's so late.
Why are you still awake?
I was just thinking about some things.
About
the Crown Prince?
His Highness has been recuperating
in a Taoist temple for a long time.
He's long past the age
for his coming-of-age ceremony.
In half a month,
His Majesty will hold the ceremony
for him.
The Ministry of Rites and the Court
of Imperial Clan Affairs have been busy.
It's going to be a grand event.
I always suspected that the person
behind the Tagara Incense,
who could command Cui Jinbai
and the Embroidered Envoy
might be one of the princes.
But now it seems, Crown Prince is frail
and has been ill for a long time.
It's impossible for him
to know martial arts.
If he is truly destined
for a short life,
he wouldn't be obsessed
with power struggles.
He and I
wouldn't become enemies
due to a change in our positions.
Are you saying
you've decided
to marry Crown Prince?
If he agrees,
I will form an alliance
with the East Palace.
Three to five years
is enough time to lay the groundwork,
appoint capable officials,
ensure stability in northwest
and protect the Duke of Wei's Manor.
I can also secure a peaceful life
for myself.
In exchange,
I'll do everything in my power to help
him find the person who poisoned him.
The Crown Prince and I
will get along like family.
Cure my eye condition?
Physician Xie said
that Commandery Princess
is completely devoted to you.
She's frantically searching
for a prescription
and a cure for your color blindness.
Is what you're saying true?
It's true.
She sent a letter in her own hand,
inviting Hua Fuhai
to discuss an important matter.
Your Highness,
you should go see her as Hua Fuhai.
That way, you can understand
her true intentions.
(I have an important matter to discuss.
Meet me at Weiyu Tower. Shen Xihe.)
Greetings, Your Highness.
Please have a seat, sir.
Thank you, Your Highness.
I'd like to ask for your help
with something, Young Master Hua.
Please, just tell me what you need.
You have friends all over the world.
Could you help me find out
where I can find the wild bees
that can cure an eye condition?
I also saw the imperial notice posted
by His Majesty seeking a cure.
Forgive me for asking,
but are you seeking this cure
for the Crown Prince of the East Palace?
Yes.
And how do you propose
to conduct this transaction with me?
I can promise you
the markets of northwest.
The horses, cattle,
and sheep of northwest,
as well as its silk and jade,
are what every merchant dreams of.
Every single one is a source
of immense profit.
Your Highness, could it be
that you are in love
with the Crown Prince?
In my heart,
no one can compare to him.
But the rumors say
the Crown Prince is destined
for a short life.
People always measure a marriage
by its length.
But they don't realize
that a resentful couple can spend
decades together under one roof,
their hearts wearing each other down
until they become strangers,
the fire in their hearts
fading like a dying lamp.
If a union is true,
then even if it's as brief
as the morning dew,
it's better than a hundred years of
empty entanglement like a withered vine.
A single night of true love
is worth more than an eternity.
You have been so sincere
and your promise is so generous.
I will certainly do everything
in my power to help.
Xihe,
you've been in the imperial capital
for some time now.
Which prince have you chosen
to be your husband?
Your Majesty's princes
are all exceptional men.
But I
only have eyes for the Crown Prince.
These past few days,
you haven't smiled
at any of the other princes.
Instead, you've been going
to the East Palace
quite frequently.
However,
you should be aware
of the Crown Prince's
frail constitution.
I admire His Highness's
character and talent.
A spiritual connection is more important
than spending a lifetime together.
I only wish for us
to live in mutual respect,
supporting each other
through thick and thin,
and create a beautiful story together.
Very well.
However,
I know what your father wants.
Your father wishes for you
to marry the Ninth Prince, Prince Lie.
My marriage is my own affair.
The Crown Prince is also my own choice.
Huayong is my most beloved son.
Since you admire him,
I am very pleased.
I think
we should wait
until his health improves a bit.
Then I
will ask for his opinion.
We can make a final decision after that.
As for your father,
I will inform him beforehand.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your Highness.
I have been by your side
since I was a child,
and I have never seen you
so deeply troubled.
Today,
Commandery Princess went
to see His Majesty.
She said that among all the princes,
she only has feelings for me.
Then what did she say
when you were disguised as Hua Fuhai?
She said,
"Even if it's as brief
as the morning dew,
it's better than a hundred years of
empty entanglement like a withered vine.
A single night of true love
is worth more than an eternity."
Your Highness,
you see,
in her eyes,
mutual affection
is more important
than spending every day together.
She may not care about
how long I have to live,
but I must consider her future.
Your Highness,
if you truly care for her,
you shouldn't be so indifferent
about life and death.
Now that the other princes
are out of the running,
you are her future husband.
You must pull yourself together,
find an antidote,
and grow old with her.
(Prince Xin's Manor)
Changqing,
I still can't get over her.
I can't even bear to hear her name
mentioned alongside someone else's.
Even if she wants
to marry the Crown Prince,
it's not for love.
What do you mean, Changqing?
Although Shen Xihe
often visits the East Palace,
I have never seen
any love for Huayong in her eyes.
If a marriage isn't for love,
then it must be for personal gain.
Personal gain?
Huayong has always been frail
and sickly.
If something were to happen...
Who would protect northwest for
Commandery Princess in the future?
As a former Crown Princess,
which new emperor would tolerate her?
Don't underestimate ladies.
A lady is also capable
of overturning the world.
The harem has no empress.
It would be perfectly reasonable
for Shen Xihe
to manage the six palaces
as the Crown Princess.
At that time, the entire harem
would fall into her hands.
Her father is the Duke of Wei.
Her maternal grandfather
is the Grand Censor.
She is also on good terms
with the heir of the Marquis of Shunan.
Any scheme of hers
is not just a fantasy.
If this path succeeds,
northwest will have
nothing to worry about.
The Shen family
will become truly unshakable.
So that's it.
So this is where I lost.
Changying,
if Shen Xihe's intentions
are truly as I suspect,
then you rushing to her side recklessly
is just like a moth to a flame.
Greetings, Your Highness.
I had you thoroughly investigate
Commandery Princess Zhaoning.
Did you find anything unusual?
Commandery Princess Zhaoning
did indeed grow up in northwest.
There is only one peculiar matter.
Speak.
On her journey from northwest
to the imperial capital,
she was passing
through Lingxiang County by boat
when she fell into the river.
She nearly lost her life.
The Observatory Official also said
that on that day,
two moons appeared in the sky.
The star gate opened wide.
It was a celestial anomaly.
Two moons in the sky?
The star gate opened wide...
(Gu Qingshu, the Gu's Second Daughter)
Brother-in-law.
Didn't I tell you?
Don't stay cooped up
in the manor all day.
Go out for a walk more often.
I've arranged for guards
around the manor.
You don't have to worry at all.
Three years ago, when
the Gu family fell into misfortune,
you risked the crime
of deceiving the emperor,
falsely claiming I had died of illness
to save me.
I don't want to appear before the world
for fear of causing you trouble.
I never intended
for you to hide
for the rest of your life.
This time,
from among the talented men
selected by the court,
I will choose a reliable young man
and arrange a good marriage for you.
Once you leave the imperial capital
and change your name,
the world is vast,
and you'll have no more worries.
Shu,
I came today
because I wanted to ask you something.
Did your older sister
have any connection
with Commandery Princess Zhaoning,
the Duke of Wei's daughter?
One was in the imperial capital,
the other in northwest.
How could they have known each other?
It's been three years
since my sister passed away.
Why are you still asking about her past?
Brother-in-law,
since I moved into this manor,
you've only visited me three times.
The first time,
you asked if I had any
of my sister's belongings.
The second time,
you took me to pay respects
at my sister's grave.
The third time is today.
And again,
you're asking about my sister.
My sister never loved you.
But in your eyes,
you still can't see anyone else.
Heaven gave me
too little time with your sister.
If I were given another chance
to start over,
I would surely
love her for a lifetime.
I would never let her leave me again.
Brother-in-law,
why can't you take a good look
at the people who are still alive?
Xihe, you look so refreshed
and full of energy.
It's like you're a completely
different person.
Did you take some kind
of miracle medicine?
This flirtatious scoundrel
should be caught and taught a lesson.
Once you're settled,
I'll take you to see the stables.
Okay.
Du Huo.
Your Highness,
it's the Commandery Princess's cat.
Thank you.
My cat has offended you.
Please forgive me, Your Highness.
It's fine.
In that case, I shall take my leave.
Mo Yu,
go get two sachets.
One to repel insects
and one to repel snakes.
Have Tian Yuan hang them
in the Crown Prince's room.
The Crown Prince is so indifferent,
yet you still care so much.
I have already chosen him.
Your Highness,
I always thought most highly
of the Crown Prince before.
But this time, it's confirmed.
The poison in his body
is quite peculiar.
Even if it's suppressed for a while,
it will recur.
Moreover, he's been eroded
by the poison for years.
His internal organs are extremely weak.
He truly won't live a long life.
Are you really going
to tell the Duke and your brother
that you're going
to marry Crown Prince?
This marriage
has nothing to do with love.
It's about choosing an ally.
Someone with little time left
and no ability to fight back
is exactly what I need.
Your Highness,
what if there's some misunderstanding
in all this?
Commandery Princess favors you
and you alone.
She checked your medical records,
and sought out physicians
and medicine for you.
Her concern for you
is something even I can feel.
Is that so?
Could it be that she chose me
for any other reason than my short life?
But...
When you're with her,
it's like you become a different person.
You even laugh a lot more.
You no longer seem indifferent
to life and death.
You have the will to live,
to fight to stay alive.
Rather than letting go,
I would rather see you
become happy and bright.
Your Highness!
Your Highness,
Commandery Princess was here.
When she heard you were asleep,
she left.
Did she say anything else?
She asked
if you were ill again
and if it was serious.
Then...
Your Highness,
about your marriage to her...
Seeing your complexion
improve day by day,
in the future,
we'll surely be able
to ride together often.
In a little while,
I should be able to.
Young Master Bu,
there's something I want.
I can certainly give that a try.
Xihe,
wait for me to bring it back for you.
Fourth Sister, what are you doing?
So what? Commandery Princess Zhaoning
grew up in the northwest.
Every lady from the northwest
knows how to ride.
Today,
let us see for ourselves.
Your Highness, Commandery Princess...
I don't want to hear it.
Commandery Princess
fell from her horse into a ravine.
Noble Consort Rong,
afraid of alarming His Majesty,
has blocked the news.
Young Master Bu and his guards
have been searching for a long time,
but she remains missing.
Take me there, quickly.
Your Highness,
the Commandery Princess...
Xihe would never just sit
and wait for death.
Tian Yuan, follow the mountain path
and search at the bottom of the cliff.
Okay.
Your Highness,
Commandery Princess Zhaoning
fell off a cliff while riding.
What did you say?
Take me to her, quickly!
Yes.
Changying!
Xihe!
(This scent...)
♪Let it all go,
give my tears to the flowers♪
♪Beneath my feet,
eternal doom is more than wind and sand♪
♪That perfectly plotted love hides
in the clamor♪
♪Between us,
it's both treacherous and flawless♪
♪I want destiny,
and also tender words of love♪
♪As night stains my eyes,
I'll gaze once more at the rosy clouds♪
♪I have a dream
of a long wind in my sleeves♪
♪My heart rises and falls,
we embrace in a sea of clouds♪
♪In this eternity, you are a part of it♪
♪My longing can level mountains
and cross countless waters♪
♪Drunk or sober, it's all like a dream♪
♪Stars sink into my hair,
the moon slips through my fingers♪
♪For how much joy
do we share this life together♪
♪Withering and flourishing,
year after year♪
♪I have a dream
of a long wind in my sleeves♪
♪My heart rises and falls,
we embrace in a sea of clouds♪
♪In this eternity, you are a part of it♪
♪My longing can level mountains
and cross countless rivers♪
♪Drunk or sober, it's all like a dream♪
♪Stars sink into my hair,
the moon slips through my fingers♪
♪For how much joy
do we share this life together♪
♪Withering and flourishing,
year after year♪
♪May the sand and dirt in my sleeves♪
♪Become the tears
in the corner of my eyes♪
♪And blossom into a flower♪
The fever's finally gone.
You saved me.
It was a coincidence.
Thank you for saving my life today,
Your Highness.
I will remember this.
In the future,
if I have the chance
to give my life for you,
I will not hesitate for a moment.
You don't need to give your life.
If you truly wish to repay me,
how about you answer a question
for me now?
What question?
I wonder if you would be
willing to marry me.
All the princes
have their own merits.
They are all vying for my hand.
What gives you the advantage,
Your Highness?
I have no particular strengths.
Fortunately, I am frail.
When I become emperor,
if you find me to be in your way,
I can die early.
Your Highness,
I do not love you.
But I want to join forces with you
to form an alliance.
You are quite frank.
If you are willing,
we shall marry.
From now on, we will rely on each other
and face all storms together.
If you do not betray me,
I will never leave you.
But I don't want
to just join forces with you.
I want to join hands with you.
But I can only offer
a mutually beneficial relationship.
I'm very easy to please.
Even if it's a lie,
I'm willing to believe it.
A Crown Prince with no faction
and no power
can, without distraction,
help me protect northwest.
Of course,
I will also help you
find the person who poisoned you.
What do you think, Your Highness?
Alright.
I agree to form an alliance with you.
But you must promise me something.
If one day,
you fall in love with me,
you must tell me right away.
Okay.
Xihe!
Commandery Princess!
You few, go that way.
- Yes!
Commandery Princess!
Xihe!
- Commandery Princess!
Commandery Princess!
Where are you?
- Commandery Princess!
Go that way!
- Xihe!
Changying!
Commandery Princess!
Xihe!
- Commandery Princess!
- Changying!
Can you hear me?
- Commandery Princess!
You've been running around all night.
Don't make Mother worry.
Come back with me.
- I'm not going back.
- Commandery Princess!
I have to find her.
- Changying,
- Commandery Princess!
a storm is coming.
It's getting late.
It's easy to get lost.
We haven't looked over there yet.
Follow me!
- Yes.
Changying!
That's enough.
Come back to the temporary palace
with me.
Or I'll have my men tie you up
and take you back.
Move!
- No!
- Commandery Princess!
Move!
Xihe!
Changying!
Commandery Princess!
Are you crazy?
Xihe!
- Commandery Princess!
- Xihe.
Commandery Princess!
Shen Xihe!
- Changying.
- Commandery Princess!
Xihe.
Commandery Princess!
Shen Xihe.
Changying!
Can you please listen to me?
Go back to the palace and wait for news.
I'll look for her for you.
Commandery Princess!
Rest assured.
I've already dispatched all my men.
- We must find her.
- Commandery Princess!
Commandery Princess!
I'll look for her myself.
Xihe.
Commandery Princess!
Xihe!
Xihe.
Are you all right?
Are you hurt anywhere?
Thank you for your concern,
Your Highness.
I am fine.
It was just a scare.
I'm glad you're okay.
Your Highness, why are you here?
I ate too much last night,
so I went out for a walk.
I accidentally fell off a cliff.
Thankfully,
Commandery Princess saved me.
We were lost,
but luckily, she
knew of a small path
through the mountain.
That's how we escaped.
We can talk about the details later.
Let's escort her back
to the palace first.
Guards.
Escort Crown Prince and
Commandery Princess back to the palace.
- Yes.
(Qingzhi often gathers herbs
around here.)
(The path she knows
is extremely hidden.)
(Shen Xihe grew up in northwest.)
(And this is her first time
at the hunting grounds.)
(How could she know this path?)
I've met Commandery Princess Zhaoning.
She was the one who guessed
that you were behind all of this.
(I've never met her before.)
(How does she know my thoughts so well?)
On her way from northwest
to the imperial capital,
she fell into the river.
On that day,
two moons appeared in the sky,
the star gate opened,
and there was a celestial anomaly.
Changqing,
what's wrong with you?
Changqing!
What's wrong?
What's wrong, Changqing?
Who are you?
Changqing.
Do you recognize
what this is?
(Vibrant and Dazzling)
Even if the person hidden deep
in your heart
changes their appearance,
they will eventually be recognized.
Do you really think
Commandery Princess is your wife?
What?
Are you trying to stop me?
Have you gone mad?
Changqing, you truly are audacious.
You want to get rid of me?
I just want you to stop
bothering
Commandery Princess Zhaoning.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
(No animals were harmed
in the making of this film)